{
    "id": "5072401e17964af693544a720c4992c1",
    "title": "Confusing Words Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The opera was pleasant but it is one of the composer’s …………………… works.",
            "description": "Lesser means smaller or less important.",
            "answers": [
                "less",
                "lesser",
                "least"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c5a93769c9aa4bfc922bfa3b5538ccdc"
        },
        {
            "question": "The ruler’s ………………………….. practices led to a popular uprising.",
            "description": "Licentious means irresponsible or amoral.",
            "answers": [
                "licentious",
                "license"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "c6f9da783895461a80e41098cf61db02"
        },
        {
            "question": "The responsibility ……………………….. with the driver.",
            "description": "Lie can mean be placed or remain.",
            "answers": [
                "lies",
                "lay",
                "lays"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e5898322cfad43338393e572c0fc7eaa"
        },
        {
            "question": "A smile …………………………….. up his face.",
            "description": "Either lighted or lit can be used as the past tense of light.",
            "answers": [
                "lighted",
                "lit",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "d91739ce9bca47fe8c255af4484a4fd5"
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… me fifty dollars.",
            "description": "The verbs loan and lend are usually interchangeable.",
            "answers": [
                "Lend",
                "Loan",
                "Borrow",
                "Either loan or lend"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "27e75388a1bb468cb8c8ae51d2c5bec1"
        },
        {
            "question": "A Rolls-Royce is a …………………………. car.",
            "description": "Luxurious means expensive or costly. Luxuriant means abundant.",
            "answers": [
                "luxurious",
                "luxuriant"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6cfb4a3c86dd4475943c442a1a544f72"
        },
        {
            "question": "The garden has …………………………. foliage.",
            "description": "Luxurious means expensive or costly. Luxuriant means abundant.",
            "answers": [
                "luxurious",
                "luxuriant"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "093266626af84920b100ee1429162e99"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the distance rose the ………………………………. Alps.",
            "description": "Majestic and majestical are both possible here. ",
            "answers": [
                "majestic",
                "majestical",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "c94360249994434db0f07ff6cfae42bd"
        },
        {
            "question": "She has a …………………………… for collecting seashells.",
            "description": "A mania is a passion, craze or craving.",
            "answers": [
                "mania",
                "phobia",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "1483979d1b80447082da756bc0feb45c"
        },
        {
            "question": "He has one ………………………. – he is terrified of heights.",
            "description": "A phobia is a compulsive fear of something.",
            "answers": [
                "mania",
                "phobia"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "8d196bfa25c549f595381ab38035ac2f"
        },
        {
            "question": "Only a man of ………………………….. could afford a house that big.",
            "description": "Means can mean money or resources. This expression is always used in the plural form.",
            "answers": [
                "mean",
                "means",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "9551ed252ea046cc9d6579758bff6cac"
        },
        {
            "question": "We understood him .................................. his accent.",
            "description": "Either despite or in spite of is possible here. ",
            "answers": [
                "despite of",
                "despite",
                "in spite of",
                "inspite of"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "89998b510023457eaddd6e6e371bc1bf"
        }
    ]
}